<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Polaris Release Guides on Apache Polaris</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/community/release-guides/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Polaris Release Guides on Apache Polaris</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://polaris.apache.org/community/release-guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Semi-Automated Release Guide</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/community/release-guides/semi-automated-release-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/community/release-guides/semi-automated-release-guide/</guid><description>Audience: Release Managers
Overview# The steps performed in the Manual Release Guide have been automated to a large extent. This semi-automated release guide outlines the workflows that can be used to perform a release with little manual intervention.
Note that all screenshots in this page are for illustration purposes only. The actual repository name, version numbers, etc. may be different.
Dry-run mode# Each of the Github Workflows that have been developed comes with a dry-run mode.</description></item><item><title>Manual Release Guide (deprecated)</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/community/release-guides/manual-release-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/community/release-guides/manual-release-guide/</guid><description>Audience: Release Managers
⚠️ Warning
This guide is deprecated. While it remains functional and comprehensive, we recommend using the Semi-Automated Release Guide for new releases when available. This manual process is maintained for reference and fallback scenarios. This guide walks you through the process of creating a release of the Apache Polaris podling.
Instructions how to verify a release candidate are available here.
Setup# To create a release candidate, you will need:</description></item><item><title>Release Verification Guide</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/community/release-guides/release-verification-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/community/release-guides/release-verification-guide/</guid><description>Audience: Committers and interested contributors.
This guide walks you through the process of verifying a staged Apache Polaris release candidate.
Please keep the ASF Release Policy, especially the section on &amp;ldquo;Owned and Controlled Hardware,&amp;rdquo; in mind: Strictly speaking, releases must be verified on hardware owned and controlled by the committer.
Verifying a (staged) release of an Apache project has to follow a bunch of tasks, which can be grouped into tasks that can be automated and those that need human intervention.</description></item></channel></rss>