<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Polaris Blog on Apache Polaris</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Polaris Blog on Apache Polaris</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://www.apache.org/">Copyright © 2026 The Apache Software Foundation&lt;/a>.&lt;br>Licensed under the &lt;a href="https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0">Apache License, Version 2.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://polaris.apache.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Floe and Apache Polaris: Policy-Driven Table Maintenance for Apache Iceberg</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2026/02/04/floe-and-apache-polaris-policy-driven-table-maintenance-for-apache-iceberg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2026/02/04/floe-and-apache-polaris-policy-driven-table-maintenance-for-apache-iceberg/</guid><description>Introduction🔗 Iceberg tables accumulate technical debt over time. Small files multiply as streaming jobs append data in micro-batches. Delete files pile up from CDC workloads. Snapshots grow unbounded, bloating metadata. Without regular maintenance, query performance degrades, storage costs rise, and planning times stretch from milliseconds to seconds.
Apache Polaris provides a vendor-neutral Iceberg catalog with governance and access control, but it does not execute maintenance operations. The catalog manages metadata and enforces permissions.</description></item><item><title>Mapping Legacy and Heterogeneous Datalakes in Apache Polaris</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2026/01/12/mapping-legacy-and-heterogeneous-datalakes-in-apache-polaris/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2026/01/12/mapping-legacy-and-heterogeneous-datalakes-in-apache-polaris/</guid><description>Introduction🔗 The data lake community and major engines such as Spark, Snowflake, and Trino are standardizing on the Iceberg REST catalog protocol for data discovery and access. While this shift provides the foundation for a modern lakehouse with transactions and centralized governance, many organizations still maintain significant volumes of data managed by legacy Hadoop/Hive catalogs or heterogeneous data lakes, resulting in siloed data environments with specialized query stacks.
For these organizations, migrating a legacy data lake to a modern REST-based catalog is costly, risky and complex due to security and compliance requirements as well as potential operational downtime.</description></item><item><title>Apache Polaris and Lance: Bringing AI-Native Storage to the Open Multimodal Lakehouse</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2026/01/06/apache-polaris-and-lance-bringing-ai-native-storage-to-the-open-multimodal-lakehouse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2026/01/06/apache-polaris-and-lance-bringing-ai-native-storage-to-the-open-multimodal-lakehouse/</guid><description>Introduction🔗 We are excited to announce the integration between Apache Polaris and the Lance ecosystem, enabling users to manage Lance tables through the Apache Polaris Generic Table API. This integration brings AI-native columnar storage to the open multimodal lakehouse, allowing organizations to leverage Apache Polaris as a unified catalog for both Iceberg and Lance tables.
What is Lance?🔗 Lance is an open lakehouse format designed for multimodal AI workloads. It contains a file format, table format, and catalog spec that allows you to build a complete multimodal lakehouse on top of object storage to power your AI workflows.</description></item><item><title>Securing S3 data with AWS KMS</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/12/24/securing-s3-data-with-aws-kms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/12/24/securing-s3-data-with-aws-kms/</guid><description>Introduction🔗 AWS Key Management Service (KMS) provides a way to encrypt S3 data in AWS without exposing raw key material outside AWS services.
Apache Polaris supports using KMS in its catalogs backed by AWS S3 storage.
The core functionality is available via Polaris REST API since the 1.2.0-incubating release. CLI support will be made available in the release following 1.3.0-incubating.
Configuring Polaris Catalog🔗 KMS settings in Polaris are relevant to S3 buckets that have been configure to use KMS on the AWS side (e.</description></item><item><title>StarRocks and Apache Polaris Integration: Building a Unified, High-Performance Data Lakehouse</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/10/21/starrocks-and-apache-polaris-integration-building-a-unified-high-performance-data-lakehouse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/10/21/starrocks-and-apache-polaris-integration-building-a-unified-high-performance-data-lakehouse/</guid><description>Introduction: Why StarRocks + Apache Polaris?🔗 Modern Data-Architecture Pain Points: Silos &amp;amp; Engine Lock-in🔗 Today’s data-driven enterprises face two chronic ailments:
Data silos : transactional data sits in RDBMS, click-streams in an S3 data lake, CRM data in a SaaS vault, etc. Cross-domain analysis requires expensive ETL and still arrives stale.
Engine lock-in : every OLAP engine optimises for its own metadata layer and file layout. Migrating to a faster or cheaper engine means re-formatting, re-writing and re-governing years of data.</description></item><item><title>Integrating Apache Polaris with PuppyGraph for Real-time Graph Analysis</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/10/02/integrating-apache-polaris-with-puppygraph-for-real-time-graph-analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/10/02/integrating-apache-polaris-with-puppygraph-for-real-time-graph-analysis/</guid><description>Unified data governance has become a hot topic over the last few years. As AI and other data-hungry use cases infiltrate the market, the need for a comprehensive data catalog solution with governance in mind has become critical. Apache Polaris has found its calling as an open-source solution, specifically built to handle data governed by Apache Iceberg, that is changing the way we manage and access data across various clouds, formats, and platforms.</description></item><item><title>Apache Polaris 1.1.0-incubating has been released!</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/09/19/apache-polaris-1.1.0-incubating-has-been-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/09/19/apache-polaris-1.1.0-incubating-has-been-released/</guid><description>The Apache Polaris team is pleased to announce Apache Polaris 1.1.0-incubating.
This release includes:
New features &amp;amp; enhancements ** HMS support ** IMPLICIT authentication type ** Support for non-AWS S3 compatible storage with STS: MinIO, s3a scheme support ** Use of Realm instead of RealmId ** Modularized Federation Architecture ** Federated Catalog Support in Polaris CLI ** Expanded External Identity Provider support ** Python package (official) ** Documentation improvements (release process, multi-realms configuration) Bug fixes ** Fix drop view with default server configuration ** Fix MinIO support ** Remove ThreadLocal This release can be downloaded:</description></item><item><title>Doris X Polaris: Building Unified Data Lakehouse with Iceberg REST Catalog - A Practical Guide</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/09/15/doris-x-polaris-building-unified-data-lakehouse-with-iceberg-rest-catalog-a-practical-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/09/15/doris-x-polaris-building-unified-data-lakehouse-with-iceberg-rest-catalog-a-practical-guide/</guid><description>With the continuous evolution of data lake technologies, efficiently and securely managing massive datasets stored on object storage (such as AWS S3) while providing unified access endpoints for upstream analytics engines (like Apache Doris) has become a core challenge in modern data architectures. Apache Polaris, as an open and standardized REST Catalog service for Iceberg, provides an ideal solution to this challenge. It not only handles centralized metadata management but also significantly enhances data lake security and manageability through fine-grained access control and flexible credential management mechanisms.</description></item><item><title>Apache Polaris 1.0.1-incubating has been released!</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/08/20/apache-polaris-1.0.1-incubating-has-been-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/08/20/apache-polaris-1.0.1-incubating-has-been-released/</guid><description>The Apache Polaris team is pleased to announce Apache Polaris 1.0.1-incubating.
This release is a maintenance release on the 1.0.1-incubating one, fixing a couple of issues on the Helm Chart:
remove db-kind in Helm Chart add relational-jdbc to Helm Chart This release can be downloaded:
https://polaris.apache.org/downloads/ The artifacts are available on Maven Central.
The Docker images are available on Docker Hub:
https://hub.docker.com/r/apache/polaris/tags https://hub.docker.com/r/apache/polaris-admin-tool/tags Enjoy !
The Apache Polaris team.</description></item></channel></rss>