<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Polaris Blog on Apache Polaris</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Polaris Blog on Apache Polaris</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://polaris.apache.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Doris X Polaris: Building Unified Data Lakehouse with Iceberg REST Catalog - A Practical Guide</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/09/15/doris-x-polaris-building-unified-data-lakehouse-with-iceberg-rest-catalog-a-practical-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/09/15/doris-x-polaris-building-unified-data-lakehouse-with-iceberg-rest-catalog-a-practical-guide/</guid><description>With the continuous evolution of data lake technologies, efficiently and securely managing massive datasets stored on object storage (such as AWS S3) while providing unified access endpoints for upstream analytics engines (like Apache Doris) has become a core challenge in modern data architectures. Apache Polaris, as an open and standardized REST Catalog service for Iceberg, provides an ideal solution to this challenge. It not only handles centralized metadata management but also significantly enhances data lake security and manageability through fine-grained access control and flexible credential management mechanisms.</description></item><item><title>Apache Polaris 1.0.1-incubating has been released!</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/08/20/apache-polaris-1.0.1-incubating-has-been-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/blog/2025/08/20/apache-polaris-1.0.1-incubating-has-been-released/</guid><description>The Apache Polaris team is pleased to announce Apache Polaris 1.0.1-incubating.
This release is a maintenance release on the 1.0.1-incubating one, fixing a couple of issues on the Helm Chart:
remove db-kind in Helm Chart add relational-jdbc to Helm Chart This release can be downloaded:
https://polaris.apache.org/downloads/ The artifacts are available on Maven Central.
The Docker images are available on Docker Hub:
https://hub.docker.com/r/apache/polaris/tags https://hub.docker.com/r/apache/polaris-admin-tool/tags Enjoy !
The Apache Polaris team.</description></item></channel></rss>