<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Polaris Community on Apache Polaris</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/community/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Polaris Community on Apache Polaris</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://polaris.apache.org/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Polaris Proposals &amp; Roadmap</title><link>https://polaris.apache.org/community/proposals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/community/proposals/</guid><description>Proposals Active
Past
Polaris Roadmap Discussed Roadmap</description></item><item><title/><link>https://polaris.apache.org/community/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/community/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>Contributor Code of Conduct This is a copy of the Contributor Covenant v2.1. No changes have been made.
Our Pledge We as members, contributors, and leaders pledge to make participation in our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, visible or invisible disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression, level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance, race, caste, color, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://polaris.apache.org/community/chat-bylaws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/community/chat-bylaws/</guid><description>Apache Polaris - Project Chat Bylaws Apache Polaris is currently undergoing Incubation at the Apache Software Foundation.
Motivation Apache Polaris uses public Slack workspace (join here).
A few rules shall ensure that the chat conforms to the rules and best practices of the Apache Software Foundation and serves well as a collaboration tool for the project.
Organizations and other open-source projects that contribute continuously and significantly to Polaris are welcome, but shall not use the Polaris chat as a vehicle for their own marketing without explicit approval of the project (P)PMC.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://polaris.apache.org/community/contributing-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/community/contributing-guidelines/</guid><description>Contributing to Apache Polaris Thank you for considering contributing to Apache Polaris. Any contribution (code, test cases, documentation, use cases, &amp;hellip;) is valuable!
This documentation will help you get started.
Contribute bug reports and feature requests You can report an issue in the Polaris Catalog issue tracker.
How to report a bug Note: If you find a security vulnerability, do NOT open an issue. Please email security@apache.org instead.
When filing an issue, make sure to answer these five questions:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://polaris.apache.org/community/release-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://polaris.apache.org/community/release-guide/</guid><description>Release Guide This guide walks you through the release process of the Apache Polaris podling.
Setup To create a release candidate, you will need:
your Apache credentials (for repository.apache.org and dist.apache.org repositories) a GPG key for signing artifacts, published in KEYS file If you haven&amp;rsquo;t published your GPG key yet, you must publish it before starting the release process:
svn co https://dist.apache.org/repos/dist/release/incubator/polaris polaris-dist-release cd polaris-dist-release echo &amp;#34;&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; KEYS # append a new line gpg --list-sigs &amp;lt;YOUR KEY ID HERE&amp;gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; KEYS # append signatures gpg --armor --export &amp;lt;YOUR KEY ID HERE&amp;gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; KEYS # append public key block svn commit -m &amp;#34;add key for &amp;lt;YOUR NAME HERE&amp;gt;&amp;#34; To send the key to the Ubuntu key-server, Apache Nexus needs it to validate published artifacts:</description></item></channel></rss>